

Waterfront 173 – 5658SH Eindhoven (Netherlands)

□ (+31) 06300 790 77 | ■ alex.duarte@asml.com | # leaxsd.github.io/eng | □ leaxsd | □ alexphys

About Me

I am a PhD physicist and Data Scientist with experience in experimental optics, deep learning and computer vision. I was born in the South of Brazil and moved to Europe in 2011, where I have been working in different countries; Germany (Heidelberg), UK (Oxford), Spain (Barcelona) and currently in The Netherlands (Eindhoven). My professional focus is solving technical challenges, applying physics knowledge and state-of-the-art computational tools, like machine learning and image processing.

Personal Interests: Cinema, Filmmaker, Music, Museums, Beach, Eating good food, Coffee, Craft Beers, ...

Skills _____

Programming Python (Advanced), C++ (Basic), LabView (Intermidiate), MatLab (Intermidiate)

Databases Pandas, MySQL, MongoDB, Amazon Web Service, Gogle Cloud Service

Machine Learning tools PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Scipy, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV

Machine Learning Methods U-Net, Faster R-CNN, Autoencoders, XGBoost, ConvNets, PCA, t-SNE

Experience _____

ASML - Advanced Algorithm Development and Optimization

Eindhoven, Netherlands

2020 - current

ASML

- YieldStar Metrology Overlay Inference
- · Physics-Infromed Deep Learning
- High-Voltage SEM simulations
- Technical Competence Leader

ICFO - Institute of Photonic Sciences

Barcelona, Spain

2016 - 2020



POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

DATA SCIENTIST

- Molecular Nanophotonics Group Prof. Niek van Hulst
- Deep Learning single molecule localization
- Single molecule fluorescence
- Scanning microscopy



Oxford University

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

- Kukura Lab Prof. Phillip Kukura
- Wide-field microscopy
- Ultrafast spectroscopy
- Biomolecular dynamics

Oxford, United Kingdom

2014 - 2016

Education



Heidelberg University

PhD in Physics

- Motzkus Group Prof. Marcus Motzkus
- Vibrational microscopy
- Coherent Raman spectroscopy
- Tissues and carbon nanotubes studies

Heidelberg, Germany 2011 - 2013



UFRGS (Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul)

Porto Alegre, Brazil 2009 - 2014

M.Sc. and PhD in Physics

- PhD Thesis Multiplex CARS applied to carbon nanotubes and brain tissues
- Laboratory instrumentation
- Physics and Optics fundamentals

Projects.

Image Processing & Machine Learning

PROJECTS RELATED WITH WAFER METROLOGY

ASML (Current)

Deep Learning Localization Super-Resolution Microscopy

OBJECT DETECTION FOR SINGLE MOLECULE LOCALIZATION IMAGE RECONSTRUCTION

ICFO (2020)

IMC cells segmentation

CELLS SEGMENTATION OF IMAGING MASS CYTOMETRY IMAGES

Ai.Vali (2019)

Endoscopy Image Classification

ENDOSCOPY TISSUES CLASSIFICATION WITH DEEP LEARNING

Ai.Vali (2019)

Properties Price Prediction

PREDICTION OF THE SALE PRICE OF PROPERTIES IN LONDON

SharpestMinds (2017)

Multiplex coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering microspectroscopy of brain tissue with higher ranking data classification for biomedical imaging

CHRISTOPH POHLING, THOMAS BOCKLITZ, ALEX S. DUARTE, CINZIA EMMANUELLO, MARIANA S. ISHIKAWA, BENJAMIN DIETZECK, TIAGO BUCKUP, ORTRUD UCKERMANN, GABRIELE SCHACKERT, MATTHIAS KIRSCH, MICHAEL SCHMITT, JÜRGEN POPP AND MARCUS MOTZKUS

Journal of Biomedical Optics (2017)

DOI:10.1117/1.jbo.22.6.066005

Wide-Field Detected Fourier Transform CARS Microscopy ALEX SOARES DUARTE, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, PHILIPP KUKURA

Scientifc Reports (2016) DOI:10.1038/srep37516

Sub-10 fs Time-Resolved Vibronic Optical Microscopy

CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, JONG MIN LIM, TORSTEN WENDE, ALEX S. DUARTE, LIMENG NI, QIFEI GU, ADITYA SADHANALA, AKSHAY RAO, AND PHILIPP KUKURA

J. Physical Chemistry Letters (2016)

DOI:10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b02387

Barrierless Photoisomerization of 11-cis Retinal Protonated Schiff Base in Solution

GIOVANNI BASSOLINO, TINA SOVDAT, ALEX SOARES DUARTE, JONG MIN LIM, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, MATZ Liebel, Barbara Odell, Timothy D. W. Claridge, Stephen P. Fletcher and Philipp Kukura

Journal of American Chemistry Society (2015)

DOI:10.1002/10.1021/jacs.5b06492

Chemical imaging of lignocellulosic biomass by CARS microscopy

CHRISTOPH POHLING, CHRISTIAN BRACKMANN, ALEX DUARTE, TIAGO BUCKUP, ANNIKA ENEJDER AND MARCUS Motzkus

Journal of Biophotonics (2014) DOI:10.1002/jbio.201300052

Mapping impurity of single-walled carbon nanotubes in bulk samples with multiplex coherent anti-stokes Raman microscopy ALEX S. DUARTE, JEAN REHBINDER, RICARDO R. B. CORREIA, TIAGO BUCKUP AND MARCUS MOTZKUS

Nano Letters (2013)

DOI:10.1021/nl304371x